

# Sarang Waghaye

**Senior Software Engineer** 

Address- 7 Avenues, Near Balewadi stadium , Balewadi, Pune 9766366930 sarang2312@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

Senior Software Engineer with total 5+ years of experience in IT industry and 3+ years of experience in DevOps with handson knowledge in Production deployment, AWS, architecting/automating and optimizing mission critical deployments over large infrastructure, creating POCs. Proficient with configuration management tools, Infrastructure provisioning, and in developing CI/CD pipelines.

## **SKILLS/TOOLS**

- Jenkins
- Ansible
- GIT
- · Apache Tomcat, Nginx
- Docker
- Kubernetes(using kops)
- AWS (EC2, S3, VPC, ECR, lambda, AWS-CLI)

## **EDUCATION**

B.E (CSE) – 2014 SRTMU, Nanded

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, Wipro Technologies (Pune)**

Holmes For business (HFB) — (2018 – Present)

- Built and deployed docker containers for implementing microservice architecture.
- Created 700+ CI-CD pipelines for different solutions in Jenkins to build docker images.
- Monitor/Resolved Disk space issues on solutions servers (Sensu).
- Prepared document for containerized application/Solutions deployment.
- Set up docker swarm and stack deployment on AWS using Ansible and Terraform
- Developed Shell Scripts for automation purpose
- Utilized AWS CLI to automatic backups of ephemeral data stores to S3 buckets.
- Create / Managing buckets on S3 and store database and logs backup.
- Implement and manage continuous delivery systems and methodologies on AWS.
- Used Container Orchestration like Docker swarm was used in some deployments
- Jenkins installation using existing Jenkins configuration (JCaac)
- Worked on Jenkins build failure issue.
- Worked on AWS code commit, build, deploy, pipeline.
- Administrator users from GitLab on developer demand.
- Troubleshooting issues when Docker services were not able to connect with other services.
- Developed Shell Scripts for automation purpose.
- Have knowledge of Sonarqube, nexus repository.

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER, Wipro Technologies (Pune)** VSDM

Vodafone secure device management: - 2017-2018

- Vodafone Secure Device Manager (VSDM) is a MDM (Mobile Device Management Technology) used for handling the enterprise
- Client based on bring your own device policy where Vodafone uses AirWatch tool as VSDM for managing this on premise
- Application for remotely managing and setting the compliance policy on the Vodafone client devices.

#### MDM (AirWatch) Support as L2:

Handling mobile devices of customer through AirWatch portal, compliance their policies, issues, reports according to object. Responsibilities:-

- Handling day-today MDM issues faced by the End Users/Client/Application.
- Create demo account in GEM portal for presentation for new clients.
- Monitor the IT Infra structure for its availability, capacity usage, hardware, OS errors and Failures. Handle Level 2 incident / problem determination and resolution on a 24x5 basis and queries within the agreed service levels.
- Enduring the SSL certificate renewal process on all production and Test servers.
- Designed AMI images of EC2 Instances by employing AWS CLI and GUI.
- Created and Managed User Accounts, Shared Folders, Reporting, Group Policy Restrictions.
- Infrastructure Development on AWS by employing services such as EC2, RDS, Cloud Front, Cloud Watch, VPC, etc
- Creating/Managing AMI/Snapshots/Volumes, Monitoring AWS resources (CPU, Memory, EBS)

## **INTERESTS**

- · Cricket, Badminton, football
- Swimming

## **ACHIVEMENTS**

- National & State level Certificate in Football.
- Participated in ICT Zone B: Represented a team on behalf of college. Active participation in MIT Pune National Annual Event.
- Various sport certificates in college annual gathering.
- Organized various sports as well as cultural events during Annual Social Gathering.
- Wipro excellent contribution award

## **STRENGTH**

- Hard Working
- Quick Learner
- Punctual

### **Previous Organization:-**

- 1- Cognizant Technology Solutions on VDA info. Solution payroll Designation: Customer Support Engineer (2016- 2017)
- Incident Management (Handling tickets).
- Responsible for solving user queries through RDP from BMC remedy tool.
- · Handling server's visibility and hardware.
- Solving tickets through remotely, deployment activities.
- Citrix issues, VPN issues, compliance.

#### 2- WNS Global Services Pvt Ltd

Designation: Associate-Ops- (14May 2015 -07 Dec 2015)

- Working on JIRA ticketing tool for resolution of INCs
- · Working within SLA
- · Maintain travelling customer data.

#### **Certifications:-**

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate certificate
- · AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner certificate